Miscellaneous letters collection
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Charcot, Jean Martin, Paris, note to B. W. Austen [?], 1893 August 13 (Box 1 A-F)
  Charcot presents his compliments to M. B. W. Austen or Austin, who may have requested a signature. Also in the folder is a note on two eminent physicains and scientists and an engraving from a magazine of Charcot. Madeline Stanton suggested that this material may have been collected by Harvey Cushing's father, Henry Kirke Cushing.
- Chase, Salmon P., U. S. Treasury Department, to Alexander Jamieson, Collector of Customs, Alexandria, Va., 1863 April 15 (Box 1 A-F)
  Chase sends his Civil War regulations approved by Congress concerning permits for transport and trading with those who are in "insurrection." Letter purchased from Forest H. Sweet, December 1958.
- Chase, Salmon P., Washington, D.C., autograph sentiment, 1861 March 7 (Box 1 A-F)
  "He that ruleth over men must be just, ruling in the fear of the Lord." Purchased from Forest H. Sweet. Gift of John Fulton, 1959.
- [Chastenet de] Puységur, [Armand-Marie Jacques], near Soissons, to [Joseph] Deleuze, Paris, 1807 October 6 (Box 1 A-F)
  On Puységur's successes on treatments by mesmerism. Letter was either from Clements C. Fry or purchased with funds donated by him.
- Choulant, Ludwig, Dresden, to Karl Wilhelm Dindorf, 1831 February 3 (Box 1 A-F)
- Clark, J. A., to "My dear Boot", no date (Box 1 A-F)
  Mentions Dr. Warren, natural history, and Dr. Jackson, so he may be referring to John Collins Warren and Boston.
- Cline, Henry, to Mr. Birch, no date (Box 1 A-F)
  Henry Cline was a London surgeon. He is setting up an appointment to see Mr. Birch. Gift of L. Cohen, Argosy Books, 1952.
- Cobb, J. C., New Orleans, to his family, Sharon, Mass., 1831 January 4 (Box 1 A-F)
  Cobb is writing to his father and family from New Orleans, where he is a surveyor. He mentions his recent marriage. Most of the letter concerns his contracting smallpox, the progression of his symptoms, and his treatment with the help of his wife.
  Letter purchased from Symmachus Trading Co., Boston, by John Fulton and Madeline Stanton in October, 1951.
- Cogswell, James, New York, to Levi Hart, Preston, Conn., 1789 December 28 (Box 1 A-F)
  James Cogswell was a surgeon in the American Revolution and the brother of Mason Fitch Cogswell. The letter concerns some shipments to Scotland being made by Cogswell for Hart, and the death of Hart's wife, Rebecca. From the J. G. Bell and Sir Thomas Phillipps collections. Gift of John Fulton, 1959.
- Colladon, Jean-Pierre, Sécheron [Geneva, Switzerland], 2 letters to Alexander Marcet, London, 1800 June 2 - 1800 July 11 (Box 1 A-F)
  The letters discuss the illness of their mutual friend, Dr. A. Aubert, and Aubert's efforts to introduce vaccination for smallpox into France, as well as the first vaccination in Switzerland. Letters purchased from Bader, May 1958.
- Colton, Gardner Quincy, New York, to Benson J. Lossing, 1882 November (Box 1 A-F)
  At the request of historian Benson J. Lossing, Colton's letter provides a lengthy account of his career and his version of the discovery of anesthesia, for Lossing's proposed history of New York. Purchased from Whitlock Americana, New Haven, June 1960.
- Combe, George, Edinburgh, to Ed. McGlashan[?], 1847 October 8 (Box 1 A-F)
  Cover letter for a requested testimonial. Removed from Clements C. Fry's copy of Charles Gibbon, Life of George Combe.
- Coomes, Sexton P., New Haven, to his brother, 1869 November 5 (Box 1 A-F)
  Lengthy letter written when Coomes was a freshman at Yale College on family matters, farming, a fire caused by student reveling, and the typhoid fever epidemic. Coomes says the newspaper coverage of the typhoid epidemic at Yale is exaggerated. However, Coomes succumbed to typhoid fever before his freshman year was over. Donated to the Library by Mrs. Lucene (Cecil H.) White, a great niece of Coomes, September 1987. Typed transcript available.
- Cooper, Astley, [London], to the Duke of Wellington, no date (19th cent.) (Box 1 A-F)
  Letter from Astley Cooper to the Duke of Wellington asking permission, as trustee of the Royal College of Surgeons, to dedicate a book to him. Praises Wellington's support for military medicine. Purchased from Myers, February, 1955.
- Corrigan, Dominic, Sir, Dublin, to "Sir Wm.", 1869 January 26 (Box 1 A-F)
  Letter from Sir Dominic Corrigan to an unknown recipient thanking him for introducing him to Dr. Tiemsin? of Aachen. He has put him in contact with "some of the best men here." Gift of Bern Dibner, March 1969.
- Crawford, Albert Beecher, Yale University, to Maxwell Bogin, New Haven, 1922 October 18 (Box 1 A-F)
  Crawford, who was Director of the Bureau of Appointments at Yale, awarded Bogin the William A. Rogers scholarship for the following year. Also included is a letter from the benefactor, William A. Rogers, Buffalo, to Maxwell Bogin, 1922 October 18. Bogin graduated from the Sheffield Scientific School in 1923 and from Yale School of Medicine in 1926. The letters were donated by Deborah Bogin Cohen, Boston, in 1999.
- Cushing, Caleb, Washington, D.C., 2 letters, 1840 March 10 - 1841 April 20 (Box 1 A-F)
  Letters of Caleb Cushing of the Trustees of the College of Physicians and Surgeons in the City of New York, 1840 March 10, and to the Dean of the Medical Faculty of Transylvania University, 20 April 1841, recommending Dr. Elisha Bartlett for a position on the medical faculty. Letters given to Harvey Cushing by Miss Agnes Willard, August 14, 1927.
- Dam, Carl Peter Henrik, Copenhagen, to W. T. Salter, Yale, 1951 (Box 1 A-F)
  Henrik Dam (1895-1976), was a Danish biochemist and physiologist who shared the Nobel Prize in 1943 with Edward Doisy for his work in discovering vitamin K and its physiological function. The letters to Salter, chair of the Department of Pharmacology at Yale, relate to Dam's seminar lecture at Yale School of Medicine on September 20. The two letters (one a receipt) are dated September 20, 1951 and October 1, 1951. Letters are the gift of William T. Salter, October 26, 1951.
- Darwin, Charles, Down House, Kent, to George Ransome, [no year] August 5 (Box 1 A-F)
  Photocopy. The original is in the William Finklestein Autograph Collection, Manuscript 19th cent+, Medical Historical Library. In response to a circular from a museum, Darwin is forwarding an order.
- Darwin, Charles, Down, Beckenham, Kent, to [John Weldon?], [1869?] May 20 (Box 1 A-F)
  Requests purchase of two books on anthropology. Copy in file. The original is tipped into the Historical Library's copy of Charles Darwin, "On the movements and habits of climbing plants," extracted from Journal of the Linnean Society, 1867, 9: [1]-118. Recipient and year were suggested by the Charles Darwin Correspondence Project.
- Darwin, Charles, Down, Kent, 3 letters, 1844-1877 (Box 1 A-F)
  Letters of Charles Darwin to [Henry Denny], [20 July 1844], sending him packets of lice; to Richard Owen, [ca. 1848] asking to meet with him to obtain his opinion on "a few zoological points"; and to [C.H. Blackley?], 9 March 1877, thanking him for his essay and admiring his calculation of the weight of pollen grains. Recipients and dates have been identified by the staff of the Darwin Correspondence Project.
  Letter to Denny was removed from John Fulton's copy of On the Origin of Species, (New York, 1860). Letter to Owen was the gift of John Fulton, 1954.
- [Darwin, Charles] Henrietta Litchfield, Down [Kent], to Camilla [Pattrick], 1882 April 20 (Box 1 A-F)
  Letter from Henrietta (Darwin) Litchfield to Camilla [Pattrick] informing her of the death of her father, Charles Darwin. Camilla (Ludwig) Pattrick was the German governess who taught Henrietta and the younger Darwin children in the 1860s. She married Reginald Saint Pattrick, an English vicar. Identification of the recipient made by staff of the Darwin Letters project.
  Gift of John S. Kebabian, August 1959.
- Darwin, Erasmus, Lichfield [England], to his son, Charles Darwin, 1776 April 2 (Box 1 A-F)
  Long letter to his son who is studying medicine on his view of the pulse. Letter donated by John Fulton.
- Davy, Humphry, 2 letters, 1816 March 10 and no date (Box 1 A-F)
  One letter is to A. Carmichael, [no year] November 12, on light rays and electricty. There is a transcription and the original casing that the letter came in from the dealer with an engraving of Davy and a separate signature. The second is to "Dear Sir," 1816 March 10, and invites the recipient to a meeting of the Royal Institution. Purchased from R. King, May 1940.
- Dexter, Franklin B., New Haven, to Walter R. Steiner (2 letters), 1912-1913 (Box 1 A-F)
  Franklin B. Dexter had been Secretary of the Yale Corporation. The letters relate to W.M. Hand's diary at Yale in 1809-1810.
- d'Herelle, Félix, 8 letters to George H. Smith, 1925 March 11 - 1928 January 14 (Box 1 A-F)
  Donated to the Historical Library by Miriam Smith, daughter of George H. Smith, in 1992. An accompanying photograph of d'Herelle given to Smith has been transferred to the Photograph Collection. d'Herelle was professor of bacteriology at Yale from 1928 to 1933.
- Dieulafoy, Georges, Paris, to Albert Calmette, Paris, 1910 July 30 (Box 1 A-F)
  Georges Dieulafoy (1839-1911) was a noted Paris physician. Albert Calmette was director of the Institut Pasteur. The letter was presented to John F. Fulton by Dr. E. Rosencrantz, November 1, 1950.
- Doremus, Robet Ogden, New York, 2 letters, 1888 December 5 - 1896 June 3 (Box 1 A-F)
  The 1888 letter to "Mr. Griswold, Chairman of the Banquet Committee" declines an invitation for an entertainment of the Delta Kappa Epsilon Society. The 1896 letter to the Governor of New York (Levi Morton) on stationery of the College of the City of New York, requests support of a bill for another year of funding of the New York Pasteur Institute under Dr. Paul Golier. The Institute provides free treatment for rabies to residents of the state who have been bitten by rapid animals and are unable to pay. The letters were the gift of L. Cohen, Argosy Books, 1952.
- Drake, Daniel, to "My dear son", 1841 June 19 (Box 1 A-F)
  Letter of introduction for Dr. W. H. Lee, a graduate of the Medical Institute of Louisville. According to Madeline Stanton, the letter was from the collection of Harvey Cushing.
- Duckworth, Dyce, Sir, London, to Charles G. Ruttie, San Francisco, 1897 February 13 (Box 1 A-F)
  With a printed clipping of Duckworth's biography. Gift of J. Cohen, Argosy Books, 1952.
- Dunglison, Robley, Philadelphia, to [Joshua] Cohen, Baltimore, 1828 April (Box 1 A-F)
  Letter to Dr. Cohen introducing Dr. Brown-Séquard, with envelope. From Harvey Cushing's collection.
- Ehrlich, Paul, to Reid Hunt, [1902?] December 14 (Box 1 A-F)
  This letter seems to have been sent by Hunt to Harvey Cushing. Includes a note by Reid Hunt, Boston. Annotations by Cushing[?] and Madeline Stanton.
- Ehrlich, Paul, to "Lieber college", undated (Box 1 A-F)
  With typed English translation. Donated in 1977 by A.V. Piccirillo, M.D. "In appreciation for the kind interest and support to Donald J. Cohen, M.D."
- [Elie de Beaumont, Léonce] Invitation to his marriage to Madame du Bouchet née Quelen, 1859 December 29 (Box 1 A-F)
- Fairfield County Medical Association to Francis Bacon, 1892 March 25 (Box 1 A-F)
  Printed invitation hand-signed by A[?] E. Wordin, Secretary. Francis Bacon was a Yale surgeon. The Fairfield County Medical Association dated from the founding of the Connecticut (State) Medical Society in 1792.
- Faraday, Michael, Royal Institution, London, to R. Young, 1820 October 12 (Box 1 A-F)
  On Middlesex Hospital. Young was a physician at the Hospital. Letter purchased by john Fulton in 1937.
- Ferrier, David, [London], letter of recommendation for Dr. James Taylor, 1887 May 25 (Box 1 A-F)
  Letter of recommendation by David Ferrier for Dr. James Taylor who had applied for the position of medical officer at the Adelaide Hospital. There is no recipient specified. Letter was the gift of F.M. R. Walshe, London, to John F. Fulton, October 1951.
- Fischer, Emil, Karlsbad, to Max Bergmann, 1918 July 21 (Box 1 A-F)
  Removed in 2007 from Joseph Fruton's copy of Emil Fischer, Untersuchen uber Depside en Gerstoffe(Berlin, 1919).
- Fischer, Hermann, Munich, 2 letters to Arnold C. Klebs, Nyon, 1930 (Box 1 A-F)
  Letter to Klebs, 28 March 1930, watercolor sketch of Carthage on a postcard sent to Klebs, 1930, by Fischer, and a carbon of Klebs' reply.
- Fitz, Reginald Heber, Boston, to O. T. Osborne, New Haven, 1900 October 5 (Box 1 A-F)
  Letter to Osborne at Yale, discussing the medical curriculum at Harvard. Reginald Heber Fitz taught theory and practice of physic at Harvard Medical School.
- Forbes, Edward, to [Richard] Owen, 1854 December 12 (Box 1 A-F)
  Brief note. Removed from Leonard Huxley, Life and Letters of Thomas Henry Huxley, 3 vols. (London, 1903).
- Fothergill, John, 11 letters to his brother, Alexander Fothergill, 1762-1779 (Box 1 A-F)
  Donated by James W. Osborn, Department of English, Yale University, to John Fulton for the Historical Library, December 1948.
- Francis, S. W., Belleville [Ontario], to My dear Friend, 1884 October 31 (Box 1 A-F)
  The letter writer is a physician and surgeon who invites his friend to visit. He hopes to write a book on the principles of surgery and asks for advice on having it published. He may be Samuel Ward Francis (1835-1886).
- Frank, Johann Peter, Pavia, [Italy], to Monsieur, 1792 October 14 (Box 1 A-F)
  Gift of Arnold C. Klebs.
- Galton, Francis, to John G. Blumer, 1882 April 18 (Box 2 G-L)
  Gift of former Yale medical dean George Blumer, November 1950. The recipient was Blumer's father. In his letter to Fulton, dated November 20, 1950, Blumer explained the context of the letter.
- Galton, Francis, 4 letters to Moncure D. Conway, 1874, 1881 and no date (Box 2 G-L)
  Moncure David Conway was an American abolitionist, a Unitarian minister, and a writer. The letters, along with three Galton memoirs "Generic Images" (1879) and "Hereditary Genius: The Judges of England Between 1660 and 1865" (1869), and "Pedigree of Darwin" (1886 or after), appear to have been purchased by Edward C. Streeter at the "Moncure Conway Sale." They were donated by Streeter to the Historical Library in July 1941.
- Gardiner, Silvester, Newport, R.I., to Messrs. Angell & Jackson, Providence, R.I., 1785 November 15 (Box 2 G-L)
  Letter to Messrs. Angell & Jackson, merchants, seeking to recover interest on the rent of his house during the Revolutionary War. Gift of H. W. Liebert, September 1959.
- Geikie, Archibald, Sir, 2 letters, 1866 January 16 - 1917 June 13 (Box 2 G-L)
  The earlier letter from "Industrial Museum" to "My dear Sir" refers to a geological paper he read at the Royal Society last night. He would prefer to have it printed in full in the Proceedings rather than the Transactions. The second letter from "Shepherd's Down, Haslemere, Surrey," is to "Professor Bonney," whom he thanks for "taking us to everything interesting." Madeline Stanton noted that the provenence of these letters was unknown.
- Geoffroy Saint-Hilaire, Etienne, Paris, to Henri Dutrochet, Paris, no date (19th cent.) (Box 2 G-L)
  Letter to Henri Dutrochet agreeing to subscribe to a book (Dutrochet's?). Removed from the Library's copy of Etienne Geoffroy Saint-Hilaire, Etudes progressives d'un naturaliste (Paris, 1835).
- Gilbert [?], Solomon, Providence, R.I., to Dr. Erastus Osgood, Lebanon, Conn., 1842 April 22 (Box 2 G-L)
  Letter from Solomon Gilbert[?] to his brother or brother-in-law, Dr. Erastus Osgood, discussing politics and family matters.
- Gosse, Edmund, London, to William Osler, 1916 March 10 (Box 2 G-L)
  Discusses the health of Henry James for whom he served as physician. Removed from the Historical Library's copy of Edmund Gosse, Father and Son (New York, 1907).
- Gregg, Alan, Rockefeller Foundation, New York, to Takeo Inouye, New Haven, 1923 April 23 (Box 2 G-L)
  Thanks Inouye for his hospitality to Dr. Fujinami of the Visiting Committee of Japanese medical scientists when he was in New Haven.
- Guérin, Jules, to "Cher Ami" [?], 1884 [?] January 9 (Box 2 G-L)
  Brief note. "Ami" might be "Ann." Gift of George Milton Smith.
- Haller, Albrecht von, Gottingen, 1752-1756, ca. 1768 (Box 2 G-L)
  Several letters or fragments. Three are in French and probably all to Francois Boissier de la Croix de Sauvages (dated 1752 September 10, 1752 September 12, and 1755 November 7). These were purchased from a bookseller, probably by Arnold C. Klebs. Two other fragments, probably also obtained by Klebs, are in German, and dated 22 October 1755 and 14 December 1756. One is addressed to the Professor of Theology at Helmstadt. Yet another leaf is said to be the concept paper for Haller's Historia stirpium indigenarum Helvetiae inchoata (Berne, 1768).
- Halsted, William S., Baltimore, to Arnold C. Klebs, Washington, D.C., 2 letters, 1916 January 16 - 1918 January 8 (Box 2 G-L)
  One letter disusses the contributions of Theodor Kocher and the other the possibility of raising funds to bring Klebs to Johns Hopkins School of Medicine. Halsted encloses six photographs of "the fauna and flora of our camp in the North Carolina mountains."
- Halsted, William S., Baltimore, to O.T. Osborne, New Haven, 1900 February 27 (Box 2 G-L)
  On the biliary calculus that Osborne sent for Halsted's collection.
- Hamilton, Alice, Hadlyme, Conn., to Earle M. Chapman, Boston, 1941 October 22 (Box 2 G-L)
  Typed on U.S. Department of Labor stationery. Alice Hamilton, M.D. was known for her work on industrial diseases. She thanks Dr. Chapman, who was associated with the Massachusetts General Hospital, for an article on the effect of turpentine on the kidneys of painters.
- Harvey, Samuel C., correspondence on Nathan Smith, 1925 July 14-15 (Box 2 G-L)
  Typed letter (carbon copy) to Raymond Hussey, Brady Laboratory, Yale, July 14, 1915; typed letter (carbon copy) to Walter R. Steiner, Hartford, July 14, 1925, and autograph typed letter from Steiner to Samuel Harvey, on the Beaumont Medical Club and collecting material related to Nathan Smith and Connecticut medicine. Harvey was professor of surgery at Yale.
- Haskins, Charles H., Cambridge, Mass., to Edward C. Streeter, two letters, 1922 (Box 2 G-L)
  Typed letters dated 1922 October 13 and 1922 December 14 on history of science and medicine and books.
- Hauy, Valentin, to Fougeroux de Bondaroy, 1786 December 8 (Box 2 G-L)
  On being allowed to present a paper on education of the blind at the Académie in Paris. Letter donated by John Fulton, 1957
- Hawley, Joseph R., Chairman, U.S. Senate Committee in Military Affairs, to O. T. Osborne, New Haven, 1900 December 12 (Box 2 G-L)
  He has received Osborne's letter "concerning that part of the Army Reorganization Bill relating to tthe Medical Corps."
- Helmholtz, Hermann von, Berlin, to [?], 1873 [?], July 20 (Box 2 G-L)
  Presented by Herman W. Liebert to John F. Fulton, December 1959.
- Helmholtz, Hermann von, Charlottenburg, to [?], 1891 October 16 (Box 2 G-L)
- His, Wilhelm, Leipzig, to Emil du Bois Reymond, two letters, 1895 (Box 2 G-L)
  Letters with envelopes dated 1895 June 6 and 1895 June 12. Separated by Madeline Stanton from the Ludwig-DuBois Reymond correspondence in Manuscript 19th cent.
- Holland, Henry, Sir, [London], to "Dear Sir", [no year] April 24 (Box 2 G-L)
  Accepts an invitation from the Council of Edinburgh University Club for dinner on 14 May.
  From Bern Dibner, March 1969.
- Holmes, Oliver Wendell, [Boston], to "Dear Sir", [no year] April 19 (Box 2 G-L)
  About a law case.
- Holmes, Oliver Wendell, Boston, to Dr. Sanborn, 1891 October 8 (Box 2 G-L)
  On Jacob Bigelow and Holmes' piece on him for the Medical Association. Purchased from Arlington Bookshop, February 1940.
- Holmes, Oliver Wendell, Boston, to Mr. Forbes, 1866 September 8 (Box 2 G-L)
  Donated by George Blumer (former Yale Medical School Dean), San Francisco, to John F. Fulton, July 24, 1950. According to Madeline Stanton the folder originally contained two letters, the second a letter to Mr. Forbes dated May 17. It was not found in the folder.
- Holmes, Oliver Wendell, Beverly Farms, Mass., to "My dear Sir", 1879 September 27 (Box 2 G-L)
  Letter to an unnamed recipient requesting, if possible, the return of an unpublished poem that the recipient had mentioned. Holmes claimed he wrote one or two poems in his youth that he did not wish to be published.
- Hooker, Charles, New Haven, to L. R. Welles, State Prison, Wethersfield, Conn., 1851 July 1 (Box 2 G-L)
  Hooker, professor of anatomy and physiology at the Medical Institution of Yale College, asks Welles, warden of the Connecticut State Prison in Wethersfield, that if any death in the prison occurs, to give us "timely notice," as according to a state statute. Hooker is seeking bodies for teaching [i.e. dissection].
- Horsley, Victor, Sir, [London], to R. Fielding Ould, Oxford, 1892 October 25 (Box 2 G-L)
  On "Miss Cobbe," probably Frances Power Cobbe, an anti-vivisectionist and writer on religious and moral issues.
- Howard, John, to "Sir", 1789 May 20 (Box 2 G-L)
  On the plague. From or purchased from R. W. Chapman, Oxford, March 1947.
- Howell, William Henry, Baltimore, to "Miss Rosencrantz", 1908 November 7 (Box 2 G-L)
  On medical research. Presented by Dr. Fulton by Dr. E. [Esther?] Rosencrantz, November 1, 1950.
- Howitt, William, to Alleyne Maynard, 1840 October 15 (Box 2 G-L)
  Invitation to go on a long "ramble." "From Dr. Cushing's collection."
- Hubbard, Thomas, Hartford, to Sir, 1830 March 9 (Box 2 G-L)
  Dr. Hubbard, chair of surgery at Yale from 1829 to 1938, wants to procure a copy of a medical and surgical dictionary. The letter was donated to the Historical Library by Samuel C. Harvey, a later chair of surgery.
- Hudson, W. H., London, to Edward Garnett, 1916 June 28 (Box 2 G-L)
  About Sir James McKenzie's advice on Hudson's heart condition. Hudson and Garnett were writers. Letter given by E. Byrne[?] Hackett of the Brick Row Book Shop to Harvey Cushing. Included is a letter from Hackett to Cushing, December 24, 1936.
- Hughes, Thomas, to "Sir", 1863 May 18 (Box 2 G-L)
  Hughes cannot accept the recipient's offer of dinner. "From Dr. Cushing's collection."
- Humphry, George Murray, Sir, Cambridge, to Dr. Hooker, 1873 March 31 (Box 2 G-L)
- [Hunt, Willis R.] Four letters to Willis R. Hunt, 1932 (Box 2 G-L)
  The letters are: Marian Dale, Harvard School of Public Health, to Hunt, 1932 April 7; Hans Zinnser, Harvard Medical School, to Hunt, 1932 April 12; Hans Zinnser to Hunt, 1932 June 6; and Leroy D. Fothergill, Children's Hospital, Boston, to Hunt, 1932 June 20. The letters were donated by Willis R. Hunt in December 1967.
- Hunter, John, to Sir Joseph Banks, two letters, 1788 (Box 2 G-L)
  Dates of letters are 1788 July 13 and 1788 September 2. Purchased by John F. Fulton from Halliday, 1937.
- Hurd, Henry M., Baltimore, to O. T. Osborne, New Haven, 1899 July 28 (Box 2 G-L)
  Letter written on the letterhead of The American Journal of Insanity. Hurd praises Osborne's reprint, "The Progress of Medicine."
- Ingalls, William, Boston, to Tyler Briggs, 1817 October 16 (Box 2 G-L)
  Tyler Briggs is addressed as "Student of Medicine." The letter concerns Ingalls's treatment for dysentery fever. It was purchased by John F. Fulton from Symmachus Trading Co., Boston, in 1951.
- Jenner, Edward, Berkeley, [England], to "Dear Madam" [Lady Ducie], 1822 July 28 (Box 2 G-L)